Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
Once again, I owe you.
You're not going to pay me
back anyway, are you?
About the materials they wanted under
Freedom of Information,
First Interim Report Concerning
Objects Referred to as Angels
and the Human Instrumentality Project
I handled it by giving them
some falsified data.
The government is quietly
pursuing legal action,
but that will be blocked any day now.
So, should I do something about
that project as well?
No, judging by the material you sent me,
there should be no problem.
Then, I'll continue as planned.
EPISODE 07
THAT WHICH
IS MANMADE
Good morning.
G'morning.
This is the way to start your morning!
Not with coffee?
A traditional Japanese breakfast begins
with rice, miso, and sake.
You mean YOUR traditional breakfast.
What's that supposed to mean?
Besides, who was supposed
to cook this morning anyway?
Now I know why you're still single
at your age, Miss Misato.
Well, excuse me for being coarse.
And sloppy too.
Leave me alone!
I'm done.
Are you really going to come
to school today?
Of course. It's your parent-teacher
meeting after all.
But you're so busy with your work.
Don't worry about it. This is
part of my job too.
It's part of your job?
Yes?
Oh, thanks for coming all this way!
Yes, wait just a minute.
Miss Misato, please don't go out like that.
It's embarrassing.
Okay, okay.
Good morning, Ikari!
We're taking off now, Miss Misato!
See you!
Let's get going!
Ah, sarcasm.
Well, I guess it's good that he's loosening up
and expressing himself more.
Yes?
He just left. I'll leave guarding him
from here to you.
She's arrived!
Cool! Who is she?
Ikari's guardian?
What?! He's got a babe like that
for a guardian?!
They're such dorks.
Miss Misato really is awesome!
You think so?
It's even more amazin' that she's
Nerv's Ops Director.
You think so?
It's just a counseling session but
my mother had to dress up!
Good thing that Shinji's
such a baby, Kensuke.
Yeah, Shinji's no rival for us!
Don't you think she's silly?
You guys don't know what a slob she is.
Man, I wish I had a girlfriend like her!
I bet you'd have a tough time.
You just don't get it, do you, Mr. Big Shot?
All right, we'll leave protecting
the Earth to you,
so you leave Miss Misato to us!
Unit 01 has achieved the
required cooling level.
Please shift operations to Stage 2.
Protecting the Earth...
That's what Eva is for.
Come to think of it, just what is the Eva?
The entry plug smells like blood.
But I feel so relaxed here. Why?
In the end, I don't know anything.
What's the status of Unit 00's
bio-chest components?
It was seriously damaged.
We'll make a new one, but it'll barely fit
within our supplementary budget.
Will our job get any simpler once
we get Unit 02 from Germany?
It could go the other way.
Disposing of the Angel on the surface
isn't cheap, right?
Yeah, this place is really tight
when it comes to money.
We're talking about the fate of mankind here!
It can't be helped.
"Man cannot live by Eva alone."
All those survivors need money to live too.
Budgets...
So, is the Commander off
to another conference?
Yes, he's on the plane now.
It's nice and quiet here
when he's not around.
Excuse me. Since we're sharing the flight,
do you mind if I sit here?
The revised budget for the sample collection
passed quite easily, didn't it?
The Committee's main concern
is for their own survival.
They aren't stingy when their
own lives are at stake.
After all, the basis of their argument was
that no more Angels would appear.
Oh, I have one more piece of good news.
All members of the UN except the U.S.
have approved the budget for Eva Unit 06.
Well, it's probably just a matter of time
for the U.S. as well.
That country is allergic
to unemployment, after all.
And what about your country?
We will participate beginning with
the construction of Unit 08.
The plans for the second installation
project are still viable.
However, there is the problem of
not yet having found a pilot.
The Angels have appeared once again.
We have no choice but to defeat them.
We don't want another
Second Impact either.
Then you're saying that the Second Impact
that evaporated Antarctica wasn't...
Yes, the history texts say it was
a disaster caused by a huge meteorite,
Giant Explosion at the South Pole
but sometimes the truth
has been covered up.
Fifteen years ago at the South Pole,
mankind discovered the humanoid being
known as the first "Angel".
However, in the middle of the investigation,
for reasons unknown,
there was a huge explosion.
That is the real truth behind
the Second Impact.
Then, what we're doing here...
To prevent a probable Third Impact
from happening.
That is the purpose of Nerv
and the Evangelions.
By the way, the event will occur
tomorrow as scheduled.
I understand.
Good morning.
I'm going to Old Tokyo on business.
I'll probably be back late tonight,
so have delivery for dinner.
Later.
Okay.
Abandoned Zone 28 (Center of Old Tokyo)
It's hard to believe this used to be
the flourishing capital of Tokyo.
We're here.
Of all places, they didn't have to hold it here.
So, is the SSDF involved in this project?
The Strategic Self Defense Force?
No, they're not allowed to interfere.
No wonder they're doing as they please.
Celebrating JA Completion
Announcement Commemoration
Thank you very much for taking the time
out of your busy schedules today
Nerv Party
to attend the demonstration
of the new product
that we at Japan Heavy Chemical Industries
are so proud of.
Later, you will be observing the offical
demonstration from the control room,
but we'll be taking your questions here.
Yes!
The famous Dr. Ritsuko Akagi.
It is our honor to have you here.
May I ask a question?
Of course, certainly!
According to our earlier briefing,
this unit is equipped with an
internal nuclear reactor, correct?
Yes, this is one of our product's
most distinguished features.
150 days of consecutive
operating power is assured.
But from a safety perspective, isn't
incorporating a nuclear reactor
into a weapon designed for
hand-to-hand combat risky?
It's better than a weapon that
won't work for over five minutes.
But in an emergency there could be
problems with remote control.
Still it's more humane than a system
that induces great mental stress,
and causes mental instability.
Cut it out. This just makes
you look childish.
And there's still the issue of manual control.
I believe that it is safer than a most
dangerous weapon
that can go out of control and run wild.
A weapon that cannot be controlled
is utter nonsense!
It's like a woman in hysterics!
Unmanageable!
That is what our pilots
and technology are for.
You're not saying that science and the
human heart will tame that beast?
Are you serious?
Yes, of course I'm serious!
Because Nerv depends on something
as unreliable as the human heart,
you've allowed a loss of control
such as we just saw.
That's why the UN had to approve
that colossal supplementary budget.
As a result, over 20,000 people
in several countries are starving.
On top of which, regardless of it having been
such a critical incident,
the causes of it are still unknown?
I wish you would at least fulfill that much
of your responsibilities!
I envy you. Nerv is protected by a super-legal
act that allows you to avoid responsibility.
It doesn't matter what you say.
The fact is that only Nerv's weapons have
the ability to defeat the enemy.
You mean the AT field?
That's just a matter of time as well.
Nerv's day in the sun will not last forever.
Nerv Party
Damn it! Idiots! Who do those
fat cats think they are?!
This is just payback for getting
cut out of the profit loop!
I am so pissed!
Damn it! Damn it!
Stop that. This just makes you look childish.
He's just a show-off, begging for praise.
He's a small man.
But how did he even know
about the AT field?!
There's been a huge leak
of classified material.
What the hell is Intelligence doing?
We will now begin the JA activation test.
There is absolutely no danger.
Make yourselves comfortable,
and watch through that window.
Ready to activate.
Start the test.
Open all power circuits.
Pressure levels nominal.
Coolant system circulation nominal.
Release the control rods.
The reactor has exceeded threshold levels.
Output is nominal.
Begin walk cycle!
Walking. Forward ahead, slow.
Forward right leg.
Roger. Walk, forward ahead slow.
Forward
Stop
Reverse
Slow
Half
Speed
Normal
Flank
Speed
Forward right leg.
Balance is nominal.
Power core status nominal.
Roger.
Now, forward left leg.
Keep her steady.
It actually walks! I guess they did have
something to be proud of.
What's wrong?
This is odd. The pressure inside
the reactor is increasing.
The temperature of the primary coolant
system is also rising!
Open the release valve.
Insert the neutron-deceleration fluid.
No effect!
The pump output isn't increasing!
Not good! Shut off the power.
Emergency stop!
Abort signal transmission confirmed.
It's not accepting it!
The radio circuit is being blocked!
It's out of control!
It can't be!
Run away!
That robot is as badly behaved
as the guy who built it.
The compression valve
is operating irregularly!
The control rods aren't working!
At this rate, a meltdown is possible!
I don't believe it.
JA's been programmed to handle
all possible contingencies.
This kind of thing can't happen!
Yet, the fact is, the danger of
a meltdown is now before us!
Under the circumstances, our only option
is to wait for it to stop.
And what is the estimated probability
of an automatic stop?
0.00002%! It would be a miracle!
Determined efforts are better
than waiting for a miracle!
Tell me how to stop that thing!
We've tried every possible option.
No, there's got to be a last resort,
a way to wipe everything out.
Give me the password.
The password to delete all
programming is top secret.
I can't authorize it.
I'm not allowed to tell you!
Then get the clearance!
Right now!
It's me. Let me speak to
Mr. Manda in Tokyo-2.
That's right, the Director of Internal Affairs.
Well, I've delegated this to Yasugi. Ask him.
I can't give authorization for such
an important matter on the phone.
Could you submit a formal written request?
So, I just need to get
Mr. Yoshizawa's permission?
Yes, I've already got an approval
from Mr. Witz.
Yes... yes, okay.
The evasion of responsibility...
A written order of clearance will be sent.
That will make this an official operation.
We can't wait for that! Once that thing
explodes, it'll be too late!
Jet Alone is heading for Atsugi.
Time is running out.
From here on, I'll be acting independently.
Excuse me.
Nerv Party
Hey, Hyuga?
I've arranged it with Atsugi, so bring Shinji
and Unit 01 equipped with the F module.
Yes, this is an emergency.
This is pointless. Call this off,
Captain Katsuragi.
Besides, how do you plan to stop it?
By inputting a direct command manually.
Are you serious?
Yes.
But the interior must be
flooded with radioactivity!
It's too risky!
But if I make it, everyone will be saved.
The hatch can be opened manually
as soon as our control signal is cut off.
You'll be able to enter through the backpack.
"Hope".
That's the password to delete
the programming.
Thank you.
JA is the target.
There's a danger of meltdown
within five minutes.
Therefore, we cannot allow it to get
any closer to a populated area.
Hyuga?
Yes, Ma'am?
As soon as you drop off the Eva, break away
immediately and ascend to a safe altitude.
Roger.
And Shinji...
Yes.
Run alongside the target,
and place me on its back.
Then restrain the target as best you can.
You're going inside?
That's right.
That's crazy!
I know it's crazy, but there
just isn't any other way.
But it's too dangerous!
Don't worry.
If it comes down to it, the Eva
can withstand a direct explosion.
Not that! I meant for you, Miss Misato!
Well, I've got to give it my best shot,
or else I'll regret it for the rest of my life.
Target sighted.
Here we go.
Eva in drop position.
Docking release!
Roger!
We've caught up!
We've got less than four minutes.
Put me on, now!
That's fine! Just do it!
Miss Misato!
Be careful.
Talk about hot.
This looks bad.
Stop, you bastard!
Miss Misato! Hurry!
This must be it.
HOPE
Error?
What in the hell is this?
There's no doubt!
The program must have been altered!
The power reactor is just
0.2 short of critical!
The control rods won't function!
Guess it's time to sink or swim.
Miss Misato, get out of there!
Move, damn you!
Miss Misato!
0.1 to critical!
It's no use! It's going to explode!
It's all over.
Miss Misato!
She made it!
Internal pressure decreasing!
All readings are nominal!
We're saved!
We did it! We did it! We did it!
That idiot.
Miss Misato, are you all right?!
Miss Misato?!
Yeah, but I feel like crap.
I'm so glad you're alive! Thank goodness!
Really, thank goodness!
But that was really amazing! I'm so
impressed! It really was a miracle!
Yeah...
But the miracle was set up by someone.
Recovery of Unit 01 is complete.
No danger of radioactive contamination.
Except for Captain Katsuragi's actions,
everything went according to plan.
Good work.
G'morning.
Now for a morning shower!
Where are my bra and panties?
Good morning, Ikari!
Good morning.
I'm taking off!
See ya!
Miss Misato is just so cool!
I thought so too,
but at home she's shameless.
She's so coarse, uncool, and really sloppy.
It makes me embarrassed for her.
How nice for you.
What do you mean?
He really is a kid.
Yeah, he sure is.
How's that?
She lets you see a side of her that
she won't show to anyone else.
That means she's your family.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Eva Unit 02 and its pilot have left
Wilhelmshaven, Germany to come to Japan!
The sudden attack of an Angel forces a first
submarine battle onto the activated Unit 02!
It's the next episode: "Asuka Arrives in Japan"
ASUKA ARRIVES IN JAPAN